John Cohen collection, circa 1939-2019
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3. Still images, ca. 1954-2005
  - Subseries 3. Digitized contact sheets, ca. 1954-2005
    - AMNH / Peru instruments, undated, afc2011059_ph_l004.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Bolivia 3, undated, afc2011059_ph_l005.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Bolivia 4 (Allugas), undated, afc2011059_ph_l006.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Mike & Alexia Wedding, undated, afc2011059_ph_l007.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - M & A II; Mike & Alexia Wedding, undated, afc2011059_ph_l008.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - M & A III; Mike & Alexia Wedding, undated, afc2011059_ph_l009.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Hazard & Lee Sexton, 1995, afc2011059_ph_l010.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - "Last Forever," 1995, afc2011059_ph_l011.tif--afc2011059_ph_l014.tif; 4 TIFF file
    - Mike Seeger, Rufus Cohen, Sonya Cohen; Guitar, undated, afc2011059_ph_l015.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Mike, Alexia @ Chacho Canyon, undated, afc2011059_ph_l016.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Rufus, 1994, afc2011059_ph_l017.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Rufus & Suzanne, 1995, afc2011059_ph_l018.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - New Mexico, 1994, afc2011059_ph_l019.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Albuquerque 1 + Putnam Valley Snow, undated, afc2011059_ph_l020.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Albuquerque 2, undated, afc2011059_ph_l021.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Albuquerque 3, undated, afc2011059_ph_l022.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Putnam Valley / Snow, 1996, afc2011059_ph_l023.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Naushon (1996) / Rufus Cohen, 1996, afc2011059_ph_l024.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Nevens / Disc Collectors, 1996, afc2011059_ph_l025.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Sacred Harp Boston 1 / Marsha Tucker, undated, afc2011059_ph_l026.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Sacred Harm II / Marsha Tucker, undated, afc2011059_ph_l027.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Arthur Hughes' Wedding, undated, afc2011059_ph_l028.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Fahnstock Park, undated, afc2011059_ph_l029.tif--afc2011059_ph_l030.tif; 2 TIFF files
    - Corcoran Show, 1997, afc2011059_ph_l031.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Jim Reams, 1998, afc2011059_ph_l032.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Banjo Sculpture, 1998, afc2011059_ph_l033.tif; 1 TIFF file
    - Bill Monroe, Hobart Smith, Univ Chicago, undated, afc2011059_ph_s088.tif; 1 TIFF file
- Series 4. Accrual from January 2020, 1939-2019
  Large accrual complementing the 2011 John Cohen collection. Manuscripts and audiovisual materials encompass much of Cohen's career and personal interests. Digital content (optical media and floppy disks) is unprocessed and has been removed from associated boxes/folders. The extent notes identify the container from which the digital carriers were removed.
  The accrual/series is mostly arranged topically, by Cohen's area of interest, such as Peru and Southern U.S. music, but there is also a large subseries that documents the administrative side of Cohen's teaching, writing, photography, and film making career. Subseries are arranged alphabetically except for the "Original Artwork" subseries, which is arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries 1. Peru, 1957-2010
    Manuscripts and audiovisual materials concerning John Cohen's longstanding relationship with Peru and study of the Q'eros people in the Peruvian Andes. The series includes academic papers, research, and fellowship materials, as well as research materials for Smithsonian Folkways albums he produced, and extensive research on Huayno music. Includes manuscript materials related to his Peru film projects, as well as correspondence and administrative materials from his trips to Peru.
    - "A" Elizabeth Acha, Huayno music project, ca. 1989-1999, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/1)
    - Academic papers, research, 1/3, 1982-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/2)
    - Academic papers, research, 2/3, 1982-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/3)
    - Academic papers, research, 3/3, 1982-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/4)
    - Academic papers, research, interviews, ca. 1983-1984, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/5)
    - Accompanying documentation for: Kusisqa Waqashayku: a documentary by Holly Wissler (afc2011059_dc025), 2007, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/6)
      DVD removed from folder, afc2011059_dc025
    - All Bandura - Serena comparisons, 9, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR691)
    - All Wallata, Kivs and Palcha recordings, comparisons, 8, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR690)
    - Andean conference, Colgate; Mapa Musical Peru, 1992, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR682)
    - Appraisal: Textile Museum, Peru photos, 2003, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/7)
    - Arhoolie "Music of Peru" album, 1996, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/8)
    - Articles, talks, music programs, 1983-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/9)
    - Business cards, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/12)
    - "C" (Chasqui catalog), Huayno music project, ca. 1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/10)
    - Carnival in Q'eros, drafts and subtitles, narration, ca. 1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/11)
    - Carnival [in Q'eros] #1 Victor's Family, #2 In Hatun Q'eros and Tinkay, February, 2005, 1 VHS videotape (Item-id AFC 2011/059: MV0122)
    - "Choqela: Only Interpretation" (film): mix sheets and original titles, ca. 1987, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/12)
    - Colonial ideas, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR657)
    - Correspondence, ca. 1982-1984, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/13)
    - Correspondence, notes, 1/2, ca. 1983-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/14)
    - Correspondence, notes, 2/2, ca. 1983-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/15)
    - Cuzco, Peru: The Inca Conquest of AM Radio, John Cohen, Work in Progress, December, 1989, 1 VHS videotape (Item-id AFC 2011/059: MV0119)
    - Dale Olsen book abstract (about Peruvian music), 1985, 1 folder (Box-folder 47/16)
    - "Dancing with the Incas" F Stop, Preface, Disclaimer to "Incas," ca. 1990-1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/1)
    - "Dancing with the Incas" publicity, and article by Cohen about fieldwork, 1974-1995, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/2)
    - "E" (Essays), Huayno music project, ca. 1989, undated, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/3)
    - Edits and unpublished article on Q'eros for GEO, ca. 1979-1983, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/4)
    - Equipment lists/customs, etc., ca. 1980, undated, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/5)
    - Ethnological Society paper, 1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/6)
    - "F" (Funds, Fulbright proposal, folklore music), Huayno music project, ca. 1983, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/7)
    - Film making notes, description, correspondence, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/8)
    - Film project: Inkari - "original and translations of Q'ero oral history (in their words)," ca. 1983-1985, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/9)
    - Film projects, 1977-1987, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/10)
    - Films, music, book, articles, ca. 1991-1996, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/11)
    - First trip itinerary and related materials, 1956, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/12)
    - Fulbright application, contacts, and Aero Peru, 1985-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/13)
    - Fulbright fellowship Peru, bills and receipts, 1/2, 1988-1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/14)
    - Fulbright fellowship Peru, bills and receipts, 2/2, 1988-1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 48/15)
    - Graphics and photos, May-July, 1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/1)
    - Huayno film: notes, translations, scripts, ca. 1988-1992, undated, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/2)
    - Huayno manuscript, grants, proposal, 1/2, ca. 1994, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/3)
    - Huayno manuscript, grants, proposal, 2/2, ca. 1994, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/4)
    - Huayno music 45s, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR670)
    - Huayno music and cultural materials, ca. 1985-1992, 6 color photographic prints; 13 color negatives (Box-folder 49/5)
    - Huayno music magazines, 1987-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/6)
    - Huayno music materials, ca. 1988-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/7)
    - Huayno music materials for Arhoolie album, ca. 1989-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/8)
    - Huayno music pamphlets, ca. 1985-2004, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/9)
    - Huayno music and cultural materials, ca. 1985-1992, 11 black-and-white prints (Box-folder 49/10)
    - Huayno music photographic prints, Cuzco, ca. 1980s, undated, undated, 13 black-and-white photographic prints (Box-folder 49/11)
    - Huayno music research, ca. 1988-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/12)
    - Huayno music research, ca. 1988-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 49/13)
    - Huayno music research, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/1)
    - Huayno music research, "S" record labels, ca. 1985-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/2)
    - Huayno music research, articles, 1/2, ca. 1978-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/3)
    - Huayno music research, articles, 2/2, ca. 1978-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/4)
    - Huayno music research, IEMPSA record label, ca. 1985-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/5)
    - Huayno music research, interview with Alphonso Pereyra, ca. 1988-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/6)
    - Huayno music research, record companies, 1/2, ca. 1985-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/7)
    - Huayno music research, record companies, 2/2, ca. 1985-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/8)
    - Huayno music songbooks, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/9)
    - "Individual and Community Music in Q'eros" (Cohen article), undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/10)
    - John Cohen master's thesis, 1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/11)
    - John Gitlitz Huaynos, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR655)
    - Journal: Mountain Music of Peru; Pericles in America, prints and videos, ca. 1984-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 50/12)
    - Mapping the Huaynos, ca. 1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/1)
    - Maps, mail, telegrams, notes from Peru, 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/2)
    - Maximo Damian Huamani, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR656)
    - Mountain Music of Peru, ca. 1990-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/3)
      1 floppy disk removed, afc2011059_dc034, titled "40020 notes."
    - Mountain Music of Peru vol. 2 Smithsonian Folkways with Tom Turino, 1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/4)
    - Mountain Music of Peru, publicity, ca. 1984, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Music in Lima, Ladislao H. Landa Vasquez paper, 1985, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/6)
    - Music writings and film (also cassettes for Harry Smith interviews, separated), ca. 1984-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/7)
    - Music, dance, festivals; letters, references, articles, ca. 1982-1984, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/8)
    - Music, lectures, and articles, 1967-1982, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/9)
    - Musical Holdouts and Peru film: Lima miners, ca. 1973-1975, undated, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/10)
    - Nan Volinsky correspondence, 1987-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/11)
    - Native American film festival; Bolivia textile video story, 1988-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/12)
    - Nicario Jiminez, 1993, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/13)
    - Notebooks, articles, correspondence, addresses, 1/2, ca. 1956-1977, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/14)
    - Notebooks, articles, correspondence, addresses, 2/2, ca. 1956-1977, 1 folder (Box-folder 51/15)
    - Notes and business cards, 1983-1984, undated, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/1)
    - Old Peru master mix, November 20, 1987, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR706)
    - Open Society Institute (OSI) photo show, 2000, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/2)
    - "Original field notebooks from all years," 1956, 1976, undated, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/3)
    - Past Present Peru book draft, 1956, 2010, 1 book containing black-and-white photographic prints in conservation housing (Box 87)
    - Peru contacts, ca. 1984-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/4)
    - Peru film archive donation, 1985-1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/5)
    - Peru films, ca. 1979-2010, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/6)
    - Peru letters, 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/7)
    - Peru letters, from Israel Cohen to John Cohen (1 of 3), 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/8)
    - Peru letters, from Israel Cohen to John Cohen (2 of 3), 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/9)
    - Peru letters, from Israel Cohen to John Cohen (2 of 3), 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 52/10)
    - Peru letters, from John Cohen to father, Israel Cohen, 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/1)
    - Peru letters and travel materials, 1 of 2, 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/2)
    - Peru letters and travel materials, 2 of 2, 1956-1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/3)
    - "Peru Music: Huayno," 1988-1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/4)
    - Peru Negro Criolla, vals (chabuka), Marianarba Cumbia, Condor Paso, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR654)
    - Peru publications, ca. 1979-1985, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/5)
    - Peru research, 1983-2004, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/6)
    - Peru source tape for AMNH recordings for Andean Hall, 1988, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR708)
    - Peru Summer 1992 trip to Peru, film festivals, Huaynos, etc., 1/2, 1988-1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/7)
    - Peru Summer 1992 trip to Peru, film festivals, Huaynos, etc., 1/2, 1988-1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/8)
    - Peru, Fulbright, 1987-1992, 1 folder (Box-folder 53/9)
    - Peruvian community contacts, ca. 1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/1)
    - Peruvian Embassy correspondence, 1979-1983, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/2)
    - Photographs, ca. 1967-1971, 4 black and white photographic prints (Box-folder 54/3)
    - Photography materials, ca. 1968-1970, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/4)
    - Photos/prints, Peru, Cold Mountain cover, Old Time fiddlers, undated, 11 black-and-white prints (Box-folder 54/5)
    - Postcards, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/6)
    - Q'eros, 2005, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/8)
    - Q'eros, #1, Kiku, Machu T'ikayay, Qocha Moqo, Faena, August, 2005, 1 VHS videotape (Item-id AFC 2011/059: MV0120)
    - Q'eros, #2, Raomundo=Despacho Challmachimpana, Machu T'ikayay, August, 2005, 1 VHS videotape (Item-id AFC 2011/059: MV0121)
    - Q'eros, 1964 1, 1964, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR683)
    - Q'eros, 1964 2, 1964, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR684)
    - Q'eros 1976 filming 4, 1976, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR686)
    - Q'eros 1977 filming 5, 1977, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR687)
    - Q'eros 1977 filming 6, 1977, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR688)
    - Q'eros 1983-1984, 7, 1983-1984, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR689)
    - Q'eros-Acolla 3, 1964, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR685)
    - Q'ero: el ultimo ayllu inka (publication), 1983, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/7)
    - Q'eros footage, 1977, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR692)
    - "Q'eros: The Shape of Survival" film materials, 1/2, ca. 1975-1979, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/9)
    - "Q'eros: The Shape of Survival" film materials, 2/2, ca. 1975-1979, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/10)
    - Q'eros community alpaca project, ca. 1984-1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 54/11)
    - Q'eros film, copyright forms, ca. 1981, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/1)
    - Q'eros music, ca. 1985, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/2)
    - Q'eros music, ca. 1994, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/3)
    - Q'eros music, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR659)
    - Q'eros music examples, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR658)
    - Q'eros-Qanchis Sipas (for John from Holly), October, 2005, 1 VHS videotape (Item-id AFC 2011/059: MV0123)
    - Q'eros research, 1957-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/4)
    - Q'eros research and correspondence, ca. 1987-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/5)
    - Q'eros rock with markings, undated, 5 black-and-white photographic prints (Box-folder 55/6)
    - Q'eros tapes index, 1976, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/7)
    - Q'eros trip, 2005, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/8)
    - Q'eros: Films and contracts, reviews, correspondence, 1979-1997, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/9)
    - Q'eros: Holly Wissler research, 2008, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/10)
      4 optical media removed, afc2011059_dc012 through afc2011059_dc015
    - Quechua/Huayno: Bruce Manheim, 1/3, 1984-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/11)
    - Quechua/Huayno: Bruce Manheim, 2/3, 1984-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 55/12)
    - Quechua/Huayno: Bruce Manheim, 3/3, 1984-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/1)
    - Relacion de Discos (journal), undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/2)
    - Research and correspondence, ca. 1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/3)
    - Research, contracts, correspondence, 1984-1996, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/4)
    - Research, projects, correspondence, ca. 1982-1984, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/5)
    - Reservados Todos Los Derechos, undated, 1 sound disc: vinyl; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR717)
    - Suplemento Sonoro para Q'ero, Puebla y Musica, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR653)
    - Textile Museum donation, 1999, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/6)
    - Textile research, 1993, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/7)
    - Thesis research, notes, drawings, ca. 1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/8)
    - Thesis: An Investigation of Contemporary Weaving of the Peruvian Indians, 1957, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/9)
    - Titles and subtitles for Carnival in Q'eros, ca. 1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/10)
    - Translations, Huayno project, ca. 1988-1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 56/11)
    - Unidentified recording with trumpet (?), conch (?), undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR699)
    - Unidentified recording: ("sr26, cr439, 440"), undated, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR713)
  - Subseries 2. Press/Teaching/Grants/Writing/Administrative, 1961-2017
    Materials related to John Cohen's career, including phone and calendar books, documentation relating to Cohen's lectures and his teaching career, his film and photography career. Includes reviews, press, and essays about Cohen's works.
    - Academic paper about John Cohen, 2002, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/1)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 1970s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/2)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 1/3, 1980s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/3)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 2/3, 1980s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/4)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 3/3, 1980s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/5)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 1/3, 1990s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/6)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 2/3, 1990s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/7)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 3/3, 1990s, 1 folder (Box-folder 57/8)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 1/5, 2000s, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/1)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 2/5, 2000s, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/2)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 3/5, 2000s, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/3)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 4/5, 2000s, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/4)
    - Address, phone, calendar books, 5/5, 2000s, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/5)
    - Agenda, 1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/6)
    - AMNH studio pass, "Old Peru," 1987, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR710)
    - Peru: Articles about John Cohen, 1989, 1 folder (Box-folder 58/7)
    - Aylette Jenness (Alaska research), ca. 1985, 4 black-and-white photographic prints (Box-folder 58/8)
    - Billie Jean Isbell conference, Ithaca, Summer 1990, 1990, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR716)
    - Bob Dylan-related articles, 2001-2005, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/1)
    - Brian Jones thesis: "Finding the Avant Garde in the Old Time: John Cohen in the American Folk Revival," 2009, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/2)
    - Cohen films: copyright registrations and Library of Congress collections, ca. 1980-2014, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/3)
    - Cohen: Film/Music/Anthropology, ca. 1987, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/4)
    - Creative Artists Public Service (CAPS) film proposal, ca. 1976-1980, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/5)
    - Digitization orders for films, 2005, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/6)
    - Documentation related to AFC 2011/059: SR716: Billy Jean Isbell conference, Ithaca, 1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/7)
    - Duke University Center for Documentary Studies professorship, 1993-2003, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/8)
    - Ethnographic recordings for AMNH lecture, 1987, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR707)
    - Film festival programs and catalogs, 1/4, 1981-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/9)
    - Film festival programs and catalogs, 2/4, 1981-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/10)
    - Film festival programs and catalogs, 3/4, 1981-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/11)
    - Film festival programs and catalogs, 4/4, 1981-1991, 1 folder (Box-folder 59/12)
    - Film festivals and screenings, ca. 1985-1987, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/1)
    - Film festivals, press releases, reviews, 1980-1987, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/2)
    - Film festivals: Independent Feature Project and Film Market, 1988, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/3)
    - Film materials, 1981, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/4)
    - Film programs, screenings, distribution, 1981-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/5)
    - Films, various: Fellowships, feedback, proposals, ca. 1980-1990, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/6)
    - Films: Margaret Mead film panel and festival, 1992-2010, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/7)
    - Films: proposals, projects, letters, etc., ca. 1975-1986, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/8)
    - Folk music magazines, 1964-1965, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/9)
    - France trip, 2011, 1 folder (Box-folder 60/10)
    - Funding for films, 1976-1980, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/1)
    - John Cohen collections, exhibits, agreements from photography representative, Deborah Bell, 1/2, 1994-2003, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/2)
    - John Cohen collections, exhibits, agreements from photography representative, Deborah Bell, 2/2, 1994-2003, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/3)
    - John Cohen photographs exhibition, list of and description, 1975, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/4)
    - John Cohen's courses at SUNY Purchase, ca. 1991-2005, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/5)
    - John Cohen project - session log 1, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR693)
    - John Cohen project - session log 3, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR694)
    - John Cohen project - session log 2, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR695)
    - John Cohen project - session log 4, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR696)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Reports, 1983, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/6)
    - Kafka script?, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/7)
    - Marion Sumner tunes; Van Kidwell teaching tunes, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR660)
    - Materials from lecture at AMNH (American Museum of Natural History) on Music of the Andes, 1987, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/8)
    - Matthew Keida's final project (prof. John Cohen), 1994, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR669)
    - Mura dance, Town Hall, notes (Jazz), ca. 1973, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/9)
    - Music and photo magazines, 1964-1971, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/10)
    - Music from Ecuador, undated, 1 sound cassette (Item-id AFC 2011/059: SR662)
    - Musical Holdouts/Guggenheim, ca. 1961-1967, 1 folder (Box-folder 61/11)
    - Obituary by John Cohen for Roscoe Holcomb in Sing Out! Magazine, 1981, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/1)
    - Old Time Music Films - inquiries, 1/3, ca. 1992-1995, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/2)
    - Old Time Music Films - inquiries, 2/3, ca. 1992-1995, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/3)
    - Old Time Music Films - inquiries, 3/3, ca. 1992-1995, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/4)
    - Photo cabinet contents, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/5)
    - Photography at dealer L. Parker Stephenson gallery, 1/2, ca. 2012-2016, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/6)
    - Photography at dealer L. Parker Stephenson gallery, 2/2, ca. 2012-2016, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/7)
    - Photography sales, invoices, and licensing through photography representative, Deborah Bell, 1/2, 1996-1997, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/8)
    - Photography sales, invoices, and licensing through photography representative, Deborah Bell, 2/2, 1996-1997, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/9)
    - Photography work - UPS legal papers re. missing negatives, 1994-1995, 1 folder (Box-folder 62/10)